619.838.5897 | immyjr.obrien@gmail.com

TS/SCI with CI Polygraph

DATA ANALYTICS SOLUTIONS LEAD

Former Marine Corps intelligence officer and entrepreneur rooted in data analytics, team building, and project management. 15+ years of experience planning and executing large, time sensitive projects. 25+ years of intimate work within and for DoD, cyber, and military intelligence communities. 7 years leading product development and sales. Put to market 20 products and was featured on Shark Tank. 4+ years leading AI/ML solutioning and software dev teams. Educated in business management with a breadth of experience. Creative and logical with strong EQ and leadership.

- Agile Planning
- Data Analytics
- AI/Machine Learning
- Software Development

- Strategy | Planning
- Budget | Accounting
- Sales | Marketing
- Product Development
- Graphic Design
- Communications
- Executive Briefing
- Military Intelligence

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Booz Allen Hamilton (Jan 2020 - Present)

Artificial Intelligence Solutions Architect / Project Manager

Currently supporting multiple machine learning / software development projects across markets within the DoD. Served as data science team lead, client lead, scrum master, product owner, and project manager. Responsible for client interface, AI solution engineering, and software development. Handles staffing/hiring, team administration, and oversees team development. Supports lead generation, sales and proposals, prototyping, and production.

- Reinvigorated client buy-in through a creative alignment of team capabilities and client requirements. Created new value that has become the focal point for the project. Client now promotes the product externally.
- Self-networked through the firm to identify projects that mutually support each other to maximize efficiencies through cross-team communication and support. Recognized for impact.

<u>United States Marine Corps (1996 – 2019)</u>

Assistant Professor of Planning & Analytics | National Intelligence University, D.C. | 2016 - Present

Developed curriculum, delivered lectures on project & operations planning, data analytics, problem framing, resource management, risk assessment, and SWOT analysis for the College of Strategic Intelligence.

- Managed instruction, planning, and analytical support to the largest Marine Corps Planning Exercise.
- Supported 2 accreditation processes through strict curriculum program management.
- Responsible for directing qualitative and quantitative research. Served as a thesis committee member for thesis papers up to 450 pages in length, across a range of topics.

Operations Planner | 1st Marine Expeditionary Force, CA | 2015 – 2016

Managed projects through the training, planning, and execution stages for all analytical related support activities and operations at the highest echelon of Marine Corps command.

- Ensured departments met timelines, budgets, and goals throughout a 12-month exercise planning cycle, culminating in the Marine Corps' largest full-scale, 10,000+ person real world simulation event.
- Led all analytical planning efforts and responsible for the direction of over 250 analysts across multiple departments. Produced SWOT analysis, business intelligence, and operations management products.
- Established a doctrine to maximize efficiencies for department operations and to direct information technologies, communications, personnel, equipment, and operations management.

Director of Operations and Analysis | 1st Marine Raiders Battalion, CA | 2013 – 2015

Oversaw the intelligence operations and analytics during combat operations. Led training, personnel & equipment relocation, intelligence operations, and maintained accountability for all personnel and systems.

- Developed and implemented a flawless and time critical retrograde plan for \$3.5MM worth of gear, spread-loaded across multiple off-site teams. Bookkeeping became the standard for the organization.
- Integrated 4 separate intelligence departments and collaborated with external agencies, multinational partners, and adjacent teams in the creation of 5,000 time-critical analytical reports.
- Conducted over 100 executive briefs, regularly updating and advising executives and staffs of local and external departments to help inform, persuade, and share strategic vision.

Social Scientist & South Asian Foreign Area Consultant | Human Terrain, Afghanistan | 2012 – 2013

Developed research designs and conducted quantitative and qualitative research through interviews in hostile environments to provide informational and predictive analysis and to advise commanders of 2nd & 3rd order effects.

Other Marine Corps Positions: Foreign Area Officer Pipeline 2009-2012; Aide de Camp, Protocol Officer, Staff Secretary 2008-2009; Analysis Section Head & Weapons and Tactics Instructor 2006-2008; ROTC and Intelligence Officer Training Pipeline 2000-2006; Artilleryman, Section Chief, Platoon Sergeant 1996-2000.

RuckPack, Inc. (2010 - 2017)

CEO / Director of Product Development & Project Manager

Worked project and operations management and product development, to include all legal compliance, risk mitigation, sourcing, logistics, cost analysis, market analysis, design, packaging, budgets and accounts.

- Managed production runs of up to \$2MM value, handling all budgeting and logistical considerations.
- Introduced 20 new products to market in only 2 years, accountable for the entire chain of development.
- Raised over \$500,000 in capital investments based on vision, performance, plan, and presentation.
- Created new avenues of income boosting alternative sales by 329%.

EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Machine Learning Ops | Data Society

MS Azure Certified Data Scientist Associate | Microsoft DP-100

Red Team Certificate (Problem Framing) | Marine Corps University

PMP Course Certificate | Syracuse University (IVMF Program, Non-PMI Certificate)

Full-Stack Developer Boot Camp | George Washington University

TECHNICAL BACKGROUND, EXPERIENCE, & FORMAL TRAINING

Analytics & Coding: Python, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Handlebars, MongoDB, Express, React, Node, AWS SageMaker, MS Azure, Advanced Excel Tools (Data Modeling, StatTools, Solver, @Risk, Precision Tree, Pivot Tables), Analytical Tradecraft Tools. Academic Research & Writing.

Military & Intelligence: Joint Preparation of the Operating Environment (JIPOE / IPB). Intelligence Surveillance & Reconnaissance (ISR) Enterprise Management. Collections Management & Targeting. SIGINT/HUMINT/IMINT Tasking. Cyber Operations. Theater Security Cooperation and Engagement operations and support.

Productivity & Workflow: Excel, PowerPoint, Adobe Illustrator, QuickBooks, Asana, Trello, Jira, HubSpot.

Other: Command Briefer for General Officers and unit commanders, 2-Star General Aide de Camp. Taught JPME I. Supported Cyber Operations. Supported Special Operations.